<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>World Medical Innovation Forum</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/</link>
	<description>CANCER &#124; April 25–27, 2016</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 05:04:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">87933151</site>	<item>
		<title>Day Two Highlights</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/highlights-day-two-2016/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 16:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=2386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Highlights of the Day Day Two of the World Medical Innovation Forum was brimming with fireside chats and panel discussions. The first session of the day highlighted the growing global cancer burden in which panelists from leading international companies and key government entities discussed the challenges to providing innovative technologies in diverse markets, as well <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/highlights-day-two-2016/">Day Two Highlights</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2389 size-full" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER.jpg" alt="Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER" width="600" height="100" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER.jpg 600w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER-300x50.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER-220x37.jpg 220w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER-180x30.jpg 180w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-HEADER-140x23.jpg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<h2>Highlights of the Day</h2>
<p>Day Two of the World Medical Innovation Forum was brimming with fireside chats and panel discussions. The first session of the day highlighted the growing global cancer burden in which panelists from leading international companies and key government entities discussed the challenges to providing innovative technologies in diverse markets, as well as potential strategies to overcome these obstacles.</p>
<p>In the second panel, experts provided an in-depth discussion on the promise of epigenetics for cancer research, describing the complex science behind the regulation of how genetic information is processed and the development of therapies that leverage these alterations to target cancer.</p>
<p>Two panels focused on the promise of immunotherapeutic strategies for the treatment of cancer, highlighting the recent burst in the field of immuno-oncology. A set of fireside chats provided insights into drug pricing, data sharing, collaboration, and patient-driven innovation.</p>
<p>The final plenary session, moderated by CNBC Biotech and Pharma Reporter Meg Tirrell, saw a panel of oncology investors discuss some of the most compelling topics in the industry today, including the most promising technologies, investment trends, comparison to other periods in cancer investing and, naturally, drug pricing.</p>
<p>The day concluded with four concurrent focus sessions, which provided discussion around radiation therapy, oncology devices, study design for personalized cancer medicine, and the unique challenges posed by increased cancer survivorship. For more in-depth highlights from some of the most interesting panels from Day Two, see below.</p>
<p>Notably, panelists demonstrated surprising candor when discussing their personal struggles with cancer, and seemed optimistic about the current trajectory of science, with the word &#8220;cure&#8221; being used more freely in the context of cancer and without reservations of this being a crazy notion, emphasizing the reality of working towards cures.</p>
<p><a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2390" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2.jpg" alt="Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2" width="600" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2.jpg 600w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-300x100.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-220x73.jpg 220w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-180x60.jpg 180w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-2-140x47.jpg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<h2>Global Cancer Markets</h2>
<p>As the global cancer burden is expected to increase from 14 million to 22 million cases by 2030, panelists from leading international companies and a key governmental entity, namely the famed National Institute for Health and Care Excellence at the UK NHS, discussed the future of cancer in a global market. Moderator Sheila Dharmarajan, Head of Business Development at Zelnick Media Capital, started out by emphasizing the term &#8220;tremendous&#8221; to describe not only the prolificacy of cancer, but also to describe the complexity of the market, breakthrough technology, and the dollars at stake in terms of both pricing and cost of innovation.</p>
<p>When posed with the question of whether pharmaceutical companies should fund diagnostics, panelists acknowledged that, due to the innate differences in business models, each company must decide their own path, but Bruno Strigini, President of Novartis Oncology, also noted the importance of considering the development of targeted therapies with companion diagnostics, which can be critical to providing the right products to the right patients.</p>
<p>Additionally, Newton Crenshaw, Vice President of North America Oncology at Eli Lilly and Company, stressed the importance of symbiosis between diagnostic and therapeutic companies, and indicated that reform is needed for regulatory bodies to accelerate diagnostics and provide access to patients. Following up on this point, Gillian Leng, MD, Deputy Chief Executive and Director of Health and Social Care at NICE, stated that this relationship could be most effective if regulatory bodies were allowed to evaluate the drug and diagnostic together.</p>
<p>As technology advances and we begin to consider cancer to be a chronic rather than terminal condition, Mr. Crenshaw also posed the question of how to best support patients beyond medicine, but noted that the cost burden of long-term treatment must be considered, as well.</p>
<h2>Immunotherapy: Checkpoint Activation, Cancer Vaccines, and Cell Based Therapies</h2>
<p>Day Two featured two panels on the promise of immunotherapy in cancer treatment in which panelists discussed various approaches to leveraging the human immune system to fight cancer, including checkpoint inhibition, anticancer vaccines, and CARTs.</p>
<p>In the first session, panelists were cautiously optimistic about immunotherapy as a tool for cancer treatment and agreed that this wave of enthusiasm is still in its early stages and we must proceed by paying particular attention to the determinants of tumor response and resistance. In this context, a recurring message was the importance of tissue biopsy and biomarker analysis before and during treatment, which will be critical to the understanding of what is happening to patients at a molecular level and, as Scott Rodig, MD, PhD, Associate Professor at Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital, mentioned, will be extremely important in the determination of rational drug combinations going forward.</p>
<p>Similarly, panelists also stressed that we should think carefully about how we are approaching combination therapy; rather than using a shotgun approach in which we try every drug combination, we should be deliberate in understanding the underlying mechanisms to predict optimal patient populations and avoid toxicity. More specifically, Thomas Daniel, MD, Chairman of Celgene Research, stated that we should be considering the patients for which combinations are medically valuable, along with a scientific grounding for why a specific combination makes sense, which is a more tractable and financially feasible option as compared to the shotgun approach.</p>
<p>David Reese, MD, Senior Vice President of Translational Sciences at Amgen, noted that a major challenge in the field at present is a need for the development of new surrogates for traditional response criteria; as patients live longer and overall survival becomes increasingly difficult to measure, some trial designs will essentially become intractable.</p>
<p>The second immunotherapy panel discussed what&#8217;s next for CAR T-cell therapy, with Usman (Oz) Azam, MD, Global Head of Cell and Gene Therapies Unit at Novartis, referring to the current technology to as &#8220;version 1.0.&#8221; Panelists discussed the promise of CART in hematological malignancies, but as Mark Frohlich, MD, Executive Vice President of Portfolio Strategy at Juno Therapeutics, pointed out, we must still determine the right targets for solid tumors.</p>
<p>When quizzed about the future of the technology, Dr. Azam also mentioned that gene therapy could be utilized to take CARTs to the next level, which Chuck Wilson, PhD, CEO of Unum Therapeutics, expanded upon by suggesting that the use of gene editing to target specific genes, create allogeneic T cells, or inhibit signaling pathways, could support the work of CARTs.</p>
<p>Dr. Wilson also reminded the audience that the reality is, as an autologous cell therapy, the logistics of taking cells from the patient, manufacturing cells, and returning them to the patient, will be inherently more costly than other therapies, but that scalability could bring this cost down. Additionally, as Marcela Maus, MD, PhD, Director of Cellular Immunotherapy at MGH, pointed out, the development of point-of-care methods or &#8220;off-the-shelf&#8221; T cells that could treat many patients with one lot are potentially less costly.</p>
<p><a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2391" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3.jpg" alt="Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3" width="600" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3.jpg 600w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3-300x100.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3-220x73.jpg 220w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3-180x60.jpg 180w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Partners-FORUM-2016-EMAIL-TEMPLATE-160426_1542-150-3-140x47.jpg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<h2>Fireside Chat Roundup</h2>
<p>The first two days of the Forum were filled with fireside chats, which allowed for an intimate perspective on pricing, the importance of data sharing, academic and industry collaborations, current healthcare challenges, and much more.</p>
<p>Kicking off the first fireside chat of the Forum on Monday evening, Richard Gonzalez, CEO of AbbVie, sat down with Nancy Snyderman, MD, Medical Advisor, GE Healthymagination, to discuss:</p>
<ul>
<li>The acquisition of Pharmacyclics and the &#8220;blind dating process&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Doubling down on R&amp;D&#8221; to bring a consistent stream of good medicines</li>
<li>Catering to patients by &#8220;bringing improvements for standard of care&#8221; that the healthcare system would reward</li>
<li>The most important model today of &#8220;partnering with academic and biotech&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>Tuesday&#8217;s lineup of fireside chats started with Amgen&#8217;s CEO Robert Bradway and Bloomberg&#8217;s biotech reporter Caroline Chen on a variety of topics including:</p>
<ul>
<li>The need &#8220;to collaborate outside of your organization, especially with cancer&#8221;</li>
<li>The costly price tag that comes with innovation but &#8220;the need to focus on the benefit that it brings for society&#8221;</li>
<li>Project Data Sphere, an independent and not-for-profit initiative of the CEO Roundtable on Cancer&#8217;s Life Science Consortium (learn more here).</li>
<li>A call to society to invest more in cancer prevention</li>
</ul>
<p>With nine months left on the job, Andy Slavitt, Acting Administrator for the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), spoke candidly with CNBC&#8217;s biotech and pharma reporter, Meg Tirrell on:</p>
<ul>
<li>The need for new payment models because governments don&#8217;t have &#8220;magic pots of money&#8221; and &#8220;we are still in the 1st and 2nd generation of pricing models&#8221;</li>
<li>Finding new ways to care for the &#8220;most difficult people with the lowest income and are disconnected from the healthcare system&#8221;</li>
<li>Pilot programs for cost containment and spurring innovation focused on &#8220;doubling down on primary care and prevention&#8221;</li>
<li>The qualifications for the next CMS administrator &#8211; &#8220;doesn&#8217;t need the job, doesn&#8217;t see it as a stepping stone, doesn&#8217;t need to make friends, and has struggled to find and provide care&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>Praising the industry for its strides in finding important cures for cancer, Bristol-Myers Squibb CEO, Giovanni Caforio, MD, started off his chat with Meg Tirrell by highlighting three critical points to being a leading company in oncology: keeping the patient at the center, following the science and collaborations with industry and academia. Other topics included:</p>
<ul>
<li>The need for &#8220;different payment models and flexibility in the healthcare system&#8221;</li>
<li>The &#8220;beginning stages of understanding why patients don&#8217;t respond to immunotherapies&#8221;</li>
<li>The need to focus on biomarkers as &#8220;they are really important&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>Rounding out today&#8217;s fireside chats, &#8220;patient scientist&#8221; Kathy Giusti, Founder of the Multiple Myeloma Research Foundation and Multiple Myeloma Research Consortium, spoke with Nancy Snyderman, MD, to discuss her journey:</p>
<ul>
<li>Being a patient advocate, patient and business disruptor who has elevated attention and propelled advancements for multiple myeloma</li>
<li>The need for data sharing for research and cures</li>
<li>The &#8220;tough lifting&#8221; that comes with trying to stay on top of the cancer landscape</li>
<li>Partnership with Harvard Business School to &#8220;put together a business plan by which business and science could start disrupting&#8221; and &#8220;to bring the absolute best-in-class to ask the tough questions and to share and solve the problem&#8221;</li>
<li>How she made the decision to stop her own treatment</li>
</ul>
<h2>Live Coverage on CNBC</h2>
<p><a href="http://video.cnbc.com/gallery/?video=3000512872">View Meg Tirrell&#8217;s interview with Bristol-Myers Squibb CEO Giovanni Caforio</a></p>
<h2>Notable Tweets</h2>
<p>@PartnersWMIF<br />
.@ASlavitt @CMSGov says focusing on affordability won&#8217;t hurt innovation @megtirrell @CNBC #WMIF16</p>
<p>@Novartis<br />
It&#8217;s important to agree on what value-based outcomes means. It&#8217;s not just about cost but value to patients &amp; society -Bruno Strigini #WMIF16</p>
<p>‏@megtirrell<br />
Parachuting into Boston for the day for #WMIF16 &#8211; looking forward to some great panels &amp; our live intvw w $BMY CEO on @PowerLunch. Tune in!</p>
<p>@lisamjarvis<br />
$CELG&#8217;s Daniels: big challenge: anchoring IO combo regimens around testable biological hypotheses #WMIF16</p>
<p>‏@BWHResearch<br />
Dr. Sharpe: As we move forward, we need to understand the impact of dif therapies (targeted, radiation, chemo) on the immune system. #wmif16</p>
<p>@TomLynchMGH<br />
Two Things: Notable items from Tom Lynch, MD 4/26/2016: http://youtu.be/Pe85aTmrAu8?a via @YouTube</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/highlights-day-two-2016/">Day Two Highlights</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2386</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day One Highlights</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/highlights-day-one/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 13:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=2368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>    Day One of the World Medical Innovation Forum began with a wave of young investigators highlighting promising developments in cancer research in a series of rapid-fire presentations. Recurring themes of the First Look session included the use of RNA in-situ hybridization (RNA-ISH) as a diagnostic tool, liquid biopsies for exosome analysis, and precision <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/highlights-day-one/">Day One Highlights</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2369" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-300x200.jpg" alt="_MG_8366" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8366-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>  <a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2371" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-300x200.jpg" alt="_H8A1393" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1393-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>  <a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2370" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-300x200.jpg" alt="_MG_8378" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8378-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>Day One of the World Medical Innovation Forum began with a wave of young investigators highlighting promising developments in cancer research in a series of rapid-fire presentations. Recurring themes of the First Look session included the use of RNA in-situ hybridization (RNA-ISH) as a diagnostic tool, liquid biopsies for exosome analysis, and precision medicine approaches to patient care. Multiple presentations also highlighted the capabilities of the AMIGO suite at Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital, which uses intraoperative imaging to guide precise localization and analysis of patient tumors during surgery.</p>
<p>Attendees then had the chance to liaise with established Harvard Medical School faculty over lunch during the Discovery Café session, which paired interested Forum-goers with renowned leaders in their respective fields. Nearly 30 faculty members covered topics such as immunotherapy, diagnostics, therapy resistance, and the potential of CRISPR for research and therapeutics.</p>
<p>The Forum plenary opened with David Torchiana, MD, CEO and Anne Klibanski MD, Chief Academic Officer of Partners HealthCare, who welcomed an audience representing more than two dozen countries and introduced a program filled with high-caliber speakers and hot topics including immunotherapy, epigenetics, and bioinformatics. They emphasized the importance of collaboration to accomplish the goal of providing better care and support to cancer patients and their families and noted that the &#8220;engine of innovation is running better than ever&#8221; as we seek to push the boundaries of the many diseases collectively known as cancer.</p>
<p>After a series of thought-provoking sessions, Astellas Pharma announced the launch of the inaugural C3 Prize<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />. The day culminated with inspiring remarks from Greg Simon, Executive Director, The White House Moonshot Initiative and a fireside chat with Richard Gonzalez, CEO of AbbVie (stay tuned for more about the Forum&#8217;s fireside chats in tomorrow&#8217;s Day Two recap). For more in-depth highlights from some of the most interesting panels from Day One, see below.</p>
<h2>A War or Moonshot: Where Do We Stand?</h2>
<p>In the first panel of the day, Nancy Snyderman, MD, Medical Advisor at GE Healthymagination, sat down with Monica Bertagnolli, MD, Chief of the Division of Surgical Oncology at Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital, and Daniel Haber, MD, PhD, Director of the MGH Cancer Center to discuss what&#8217;s to come in a new era of cancer research and care. The panelists were tasked with advising on whether cancer research and care over the next decade will be a war or a moonshot. Panelists agreed on both perspectives &#8211; a war because, from a patient perspective, it is a personal battle against disease and we must come together as an army to combat the disease and work effectively towards a cure, and a moonshot because progress in cancer happens with huge steps forward and reflects the combined efforts of a large group of people working toward a common goal, much like landing on the moon.</p>
<p>When asked about the funding landscape and future of academic research and development in oncology, Dr. Bertagnolli noted that, when money is tight, teamwork must be utilized, and support from patient organizations such as Stand Up To Cancer is profound. Dr. Haber also noted that we are at a magic time during which so much science is being translated, but that funds are also needed for basic research, with the rationale that, if all money goes to translational research and we do not value basic discovery, then there will be nothing to translate in the coming years.</p>
<p><a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2372" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-300x200.jpg" alt="_H8A1644" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1644-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>  <a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2373" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-300x200.jpg" alt="_H8A1752" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1752-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>  <a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2374" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-300x200.jpg" alt="_H8A1799" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A1799-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<h2>Creating a Disruptive Cancer Pipeline and Winning Portfolio Strategy</h2>
<p>A focus of Day One included cancer pipeline and portfolio development, which began with a panel discussion of how to build and maintain a successful pipeline in a challenging environment. Panelists including Keith Flaherty, MD, Director of Clinical Research at the MGH Cancer Center, and Sean Harper, MD, Executive Vice President of Research and Development at Amgen, commenting on company culture and regulatory oversight of clinical trials.</p>
<p>Jay Bradner, MD, President of the Novartis Institutes for BioMedical Research, noted that we may not be able to visualize what a cure for cancer will look like at this time, as technologies are still emerging, but that we should beware of paradigms, as they can sometimes make you blind to the next breaking wave.</p>
<p>In a discussion of clinical trial participation, panelists stressed the need for improved navigation of study information for patients, which would in turn facilitate the interactions between these patients and their physicians and potentially improve recruitment. It was also noted that these patients should have access to expert opinion on the best trials for their disease; as George Demetri, MD, Director of the Center for Sarcoma and Bone Oncology at Dana-Farber Cancer Institute noted, it should not be so much easier to find the best Chinese restaurants on &#8220;Dr. Google&#8221; than it is to find the best clinical trial.</p>
<p>Panelists discussed the need for improved infrastructure that would hasten the timeline from ideas to clinical trials and noted that the FDA is responsive to novel approaches and is looking to industry and academia for advice. Dr. Demetri also noted that such an idea is on the table, with the proposed creation of an Oncology Center of Excellence at the FDA.</p>
<p>Overall, panelists indicated that the pharmaceutical industry is receptive to insight from academia, and that the field appears to be aligned in the early drug discovery mission. In a discussion of the interactions between small companies and big pharma, panelists noted that the small companies tend to be very innovative, but investments are risky. Sean Harper, MD, noted that pharma tends to be very open to bringing assets in to their pipeline, but would rather engage early on to ensure that it&#8217;s a good product, and that takes engineering.</p>
<p><a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2377" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-300x200.jpg" alt="_H8A8454" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/H8A8454-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>  <a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2375" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-300x200.jpg" alt="_MG_8432" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8432-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>  <a href="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2376" src="http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-300x200.jpg" alt="_MG_8445" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-300x200.jpg 300w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-768x512.jpg 768w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-150x100.jpg 150w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-120x80.jpg 120w, https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/MG_8445-93x62.jpg 93w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<h2>Curative Therapies: The Economics of Game-Changing Science</h2>
<p>As novel, potentially curative cancer therapies come to market, drug pricing has emerged as one of the hottest topics of discussion. Speakers shared their insights on the balance between affordability and continued innovation in the healthcare industry, which was emphasized by Betsy Nabel, MD, with the notion that we need to provide the &#8220;right treatment for the right patients at the right time&#8221; while making it affordable.</p>
<p>Speakers included Troy Brennan, MD, Executive Vice President and CMO of CVS Health, Paul Hudson, President of AstraZeneca US, Betsy Nabel, MD, President of Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital, Gary Reedy, CEO of the American Cancer Society, and Peter Slavin, MD, President of Massachusetts General Hospital. The panel was moderated by Sue Siegel, CEO of GE Healthymagination.</p>
<p>In the session, panelists discussed how to measure the effectiveness of a treatment. Dr. Slavin noted that we are facing much more economic pressure in healthcare and that it is critical to eliminate care that doesn&#8217;t help our patients. Panelists suggested that the private sector, including commercial payers, academic medical centers, pharmaceutical industry, biotech, venture, and pharmacy should come together to determine the value framework, rather than leaving it to CMS.</p>
<p>Mr. Hudson noted an inherent risk associated with developing medicines, and that the demand for breakthroughs and targeting of smaller patient populations has never been higher, while Dr. Nabel reminded us that companies must also consider the costs associated with innovation, as well as the hidden cost for future development if innovation is left behind. Panelists suggested that pharmaceutical companies, insurance providers, and pharmacy benefit management companies should come together to share risk, as all parties would be incentivized if the risk is broadly distributed.</p>
<p>When asked about when cancer will become a chronic disease, a majority of the panel agreed that it would be within 10 years, while one panelist noted that, in some patient populations, the time is now.</p>
<h2>Notable Tweets</h2>
<p>@BrighamWomens<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/BrighamWomens/status/724685238237028355">&#8220;We want to ensure that our patients have access to clinical trials &amp; effective therapies.&#8221;- Dr. Betsy Nabel #WMIF16</a></p>
<p>@MassGeneralNews<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/MassGeneralNews/status/724603589621108736">Are miniature devices the next tool in diagnosing + tracking #cancer? #MGH&#8217;s Hakho Lee discussing now #WMIF16</a></p>
<p>@Novartis<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/Novartis/status/724691948683055104">We can&#8217;t be surprised we haven&#8217;t cured #cancer when we haven&#8217;t figured out how to respond to all its dominant causes -@jaybradner #WMIF16</a></p>
<p>@bmsnews<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/bmsnews/status/724675347183230976">This is a historic time in cancer research. The opportunity is unprecedented. #ImmunoOncology research. #WMIF16.</a></p>
<p>@PartnersWMIF<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/PartnersWMIF/status/724656825027682304">.@JayBradner, Pres of @NovartisScience: &#8220;We have to beware of current paradigms&#8230; Can make us blind to next breaking wave.&#8221; #WMIF16</a></p>
<p>@CarolineYLChen<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/CarolineYLChen/status/724747692841291776">$ABBV Gonzalez says his perspective as a cancer patient has made him go ahead w testing drugs in small populations that may not have big ROI</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/highlights-day-one/">Day One Highlights</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2368</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2016 World Medical Innovation Forum to Feature Innovations Enhancing Patient Care from Prevention to the Needs of Long-Term Cancer Survivors</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/2016-world-medical-innovation-forum-feature-innovations-enhancing-patient-care-prevention-needs-long-term-cancer-survivors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=2336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON&#8211;(BUSINESS WIRE)&#8211;Partners HealthCare today announced that the upcoming World Medical Innovation Forum™ will include a focus on patient care, ranging from discussions of the importance of cancer prevention and early detection and the innovations that are making it possible to the unique care requirements and new technology approaches to help survivors. The 2016 Forum, an <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/2016-world-medical-innovation-forum-feature-innovations-enhancing-patient-care-prevention-needs-long-term-cancer-survivors/">2016 World Medical Innovation Forum to Feature Innovations Enhancing Patient Care from Prevention to the Needs of Long-Term Cancer Survivors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON&#8211;(<a href="http://www.businesswire.com/" rel="nofollow">BUSINESS WIRE</a>)&#8211;Partners HealthCare today announced that the upcoming <a href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fworldmedicalinnovation.org%2F&amp;esheet=51318971&amp;newsitemid=20160413005469&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=World+Medical+Innovation+Forum%E2%84%A2&amp;index=1&amp;md5=a27680c0a6877335e7f9d91c7424fec9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">World Medical Innovation Forum<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a> will include a focus on patient care, ranging from discussions of the importance of cancer prevention and early detection and the innovations that are making it possible to the unique care requirements and new technology approaches to help survivors. The 2016 Forum, an annual collaboration and partnering event held in Boston on April 25-27, will focus on cancer. CEOs and senior company executives, top investors, policy experts, and Harvard scientists leading the charge in the fight against cancer will take the stage over the course of the three-day Forum for a series of sessions that will critically examine the innovations in and evolution of cancer care.</p>
<p>“Technological advances in diagnostics are beginning to make it possible to detect cancer at the earliest stages of the disease when treatment may be most effective,” said David Louis, MD, Pathologist-in-Chief, Massachusetts General Hospital and Benjamin Castleman Professor of Pathology, Harvard Medical School. “However, there have been many barriers to making these innovative tests widely available to patients, including the need for more research and development to ensure accuracy, better guidance to speed the regulatory process and new models to support their value and reimbursement. This Forum provides a space for us to learn about these exciting new diagnostic technologies and to collaborate on the scientific and economic challenges that preventative strategies and early cancer detection bring about.”</p>
<p>“Detecting cancer as early as possible in the developmental stage will help both patients and hospitals in terms of prognosis with possible cure or therapy regimens before the cancer has spread. It will also help avoid the economic burden typically associated with late-stage detection,” said Massimo Loda, MD, Senior Pathologist, Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Principal Investigator, Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, and Professor of Pathology, Harvard Medical School. “The technologies we are creating and pursuing are designed to detect and pursue cancer cells at the most vulnerable point in their development: the very beginning. The Forum will provide us with the opportunity to discuss those advances and learn of other new developments in a collaborative manner.”</p>
<p>The prevention of cancer and the development of new strategies to detect cancer precursors and early-stage malignancies when treatment may be most effective – clinically and financially — are critical research goals. The experts on the “<b>Early Detection and Prevention of Cancer</b>” panel will review powerful imaging modalities, single-cell analysis of the tumor microenvironment and next-generation cancer models. They will also discuss circulating tumor DNA testing to monitor response to treatment and emergence of cancer resistance—with the objective of early cancer diagnosis before symptoms appear. The panel will take place at <b>4:50 p.m. on Monday, April 25, 2016, in the Novartis Ballroom of The Westin Copley Hotel.</b></p>
<p>Panel participants include:</p>
<ul>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb">Moderator: <b>David Louis</b>, MD, Pathologist-in-Chief, MGH and Benjamin Castleman Professor of Pathology, Harvard Medical School</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Andy Chan</b>, MD, Program Director, Gastroenterology Training Program, MGH and Associate Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>William Hait</b>, MD, PhD, Global Head, Janssen Research &amp; Development</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Krishna Kumar</b>, CEO, Emerging Businesses, Philips</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Massimo Loda</b>, MD, Senior Pathologist, Principal Investigator, BWH, Dana-Farber and Professor, Department of Pathology, Harvard Medical School</li>
</ul>
<p>“The number of people diagnosed with cancer is continuing to grow at an astounding rate and while new treatment advances are enabling more and more of these patients to survive, there is an increasing need for innovative tools and resources to address the changing needs of patients, their families and the health care system,” said Claire Thom, Pharm D, Senior Vice President, Global Oncology Development, Astellas.</p>
<p>Extraordinary treatment advances have turned many cancers from apparent death sentences into manageable chronic illnesses with extraordinary consequences for the entire health care system. In the United States, there are approximately 14 million cancer survivors, up from just three million four decades earlier. Those survivors have unique care requirements, that will put enormous stress on the system and calling out for new technology solutions. A program, titled “<b>Surviving Cancer: New Realities, New Needs</b>,” will discuss those requirements and the technologies and approaches that can help monitor, guide, and connect patients. The panel will take place at <b>4:00 p.m. on Tuesday, April 26, 2016, in the Takeda Ballroom of The Westin Copley Hotel.</b></p>
<p>Panel participants include:</p>
<ul>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb">Moderator: <b>Tim Ferris</b>, MD, Senior Vice President of Population Health Management, Partners HealthCare</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Jani Ahonala</b>, CEO, Noona Healthcare</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Don Dizon</b>, MD, Clinical Co-Director, Gynecologic Oncology, Founder and Director, The Oncology Sexual Health Clinic, MGH and Associate Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Ann Partridge</b>, MD, Director, Adult Survivorship Program, Program for Young Women with Breast Cancer, Dana-Farber and Associate Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmargb"><b>Claire Thom</b>, Pharm D, Senior Vice President, Global Oncology Development, Astellas</li>
</ul>
<p>Sponsors of the Forum include Novartis, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Takeda Oncology, Amgen, Astellas, AstraZeneca, General Electric, Ipsen, MacDougall Biomedical Communications, McCall &amp; Almy, Mintz Levin, Ropes &amp; Gray, and Vertex. ST<i>A</i>T is the exclusive media partner of the Forum.</p>
<p><b>About the World Medical Innovation Forum</b><br />
The World Medical Innovation Forum is a global gathering of senior corporate, investor, and academic leaders. It was established to respond to the intensifying transformation of health care and its impact on innovation. The Forum is rooted in the belief that no matter the magnitude of that change, the center of health care needs to be a shared, fundamental commitment to collaborative innovation – industry and academia working together and its ability to improve patient lives.</p>
<p>For more information or to register, please go to <a href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.worldmedicalinnovation.org&amp;esheet=51318971&amp;newsitemid=20160413005469&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=www.worldmedicalinnovation.org&amp;index=2&amp;md5=8031f35be853b120fe61ff34f3e6ef34" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.worldmedicalinnovation.org</a>.</p>
<p><b>About Partners HealthCare</b><br />
Partners HealthCare is an integrated health system founded by Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Massachusetts General Hospital. In addition to its two academic medical centers, the Partners system includes community and specialty hospitals, a managed care organization, community health centers, a physician network, home health and long-term care services, and other health-related entities. Partners HealthCare is one of the nation’s leading biomedical research organizations and a principal teaching affiliate of Harvard Medical School. Partners HealthCare is a non-profit organization.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/2016-world-medical-innovation-forum-feature-innovations-enhancing-patient-care-prevention-needs-long-term-cancer-survivors/">2016 World Medical Innovation Forum to Feature Innovations Enhancing Patient Care from Prevention to the Needs of Long-Term Cancer Survivors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Impact of Cancer Breakthroughs to Be Featured at 2016 World Medical Innovation Forum</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/global-impact-cancer-breakthroughs-featured-2016-world-medical-innovation-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=2283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON — March 23, 2016 — Partners HealthCare today announced that highlights at the upcoming World Medical Innovation ForumTM will include the global economics of cancer care. The 2016 Forum, an annual collaboration and partnering event held in Boston on April 25-27, will focus on cancer. CEOs and senior company executives, top investors, policy experts, <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/global-impact-cancer-breakthroughs-featured-2016-world-medical-innovation-forum/">Global Impact of Cancer Breakthroughs to Be Featured at 2016 World Medical Innovation Forum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>BOSTON — March 23, 2016 — Partners HealthCare today announced that highlights at the upcoming World Medical Innovation ForumTM will include the global economics of cancer care. The 2016 Forum, an annual collaboration and partnering event held in Boston on April 25-27, will focus on cancer. CEOs and senior company executives, top investors, policy experts, and Harvard scientists leading the charge in the fight against cancer will take the stage over the course of the three-day Forum for a series of sessions that will critically examine the changing economic cancer-care landscape.</p>
<p>Novel, potentially curative cancer therapies are coming to market, with the promise of unprecedented patient benefits. While most key stakeholders have recognized the cost effectiveness of curative therapies, these therapies also present a challenge to payers in terms of the potential spike in patient volume and high cost as many of these innovative cancer therapies are being introduced. The “Curative Therapies: The Economics of Game Changing Science” panel will bring together top executives from the pharma, foundation, pharmacy, and provider sectors to explore cost effectiveness as part of regulatory approval. They will also examine the increasing emphasis on early detection, shifting incentives for oncologists, and how integrating billing codes, bundled payments, and management fees can help bring drug costs down. This panel will take place at 3:10 p.m. on Monday, April 25, 2016, in the Novartis Ballroom of The Westin Copley Hotel.</p>
<p>Panel participants include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Moderator: Sue Siegel, CEO, GE Ventures and Healthymagination</li>
<li>Troyan Brennan, MD, Executive Vice President and Chief Medical Officer, CVS</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>“The balance of affordability and the continuation of progress in the development of new drugs and therapies is an increasingly critical factor in cancer care and the way we treat cancer patients today,” said Gary Reedy, CEO, American Cancer Society. “This forum will examine some of the emerging issues that directly impact that balance including the cost of new innovations, procedures, diagnostics and medications, changes in reimbursement, and new models of care delivery.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>Health</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="page" title="Page 2">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<ul>
<li>Paul Hudson, President, AstraZeneca US and Executive Vice President, AstraZeneca North America</li>
<li>Betsy Nabel, MD, President, BWH and Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School</li>
<li>Gary Reedy, Chief Executive Officer, American Cancer Society</li>
<li>Peter Slavin, MD, President, MGH and Professor of Healthcare Policy, Harvard MedicalSchoolAccording to the American Cancer Society, cancer causes 1 in 7 deaths worldwide and is rapidly becoming a global epidemic. If rates don’t change, the World Health Organization predicts that the global cancer burden will increase from 14 million new cases and 8 million cancer-related deaths worldwide to 22 million cases and 13 million deaths by 2030.“The shift to treating cancer as a chronic disease and the multitude of new treatments and technologies available to health care providers are impacting the financial aspect of cancer treatment,” said Marc de Garidel, Chairman and CEO, Ipsen, the global specialty-driven pharmaceutical company. “The issue is treated differently from country to country and there are many lessons to be learned from the outcomes of each approach.”
<p>To kick off the program on Tuesday, expert panelists from leading international companies and key governmental entities, including the famed National Institute for Health Care Excellence, or NICE, in the United Kingdom, will discuss how approaches to deliver innovative technologies differ in various international markets, what the respective drivers are, and the requirements and challenges that must be met. The program, titled “Global Cancer Markets,” will focus on key strategies and trends in the international market and will begin at 8:15 a.m. on Tuesday, April 26, 2016, in the Novartis Ballroom of The Westin Copley Hotel.</p>
<p>Panel participants include:</p>
<ul>
<li> Moderator: Sheila Dharmarajan, Head of Business Development, Zelnick Media Capital</li>
<li>Newton Crenshaw, Vice President of North America Oncology, Eli Lilly and Company</li>
<li>Marc de Garidel, Chairman and CEO, Ipsen</li>
<li>Gillian Leng, MD, Deputy Chief Executive, Director of Health and Social Care,National Institute for Health and Care Excellence</li>
<li>James Robinson, President, Americas Operations, Astellas</li>
<li>Bruno Strigini, President, Novartis OncologySponsors of the Forum include Novartis, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Takeda Oncology, Amgen, Astellas, AstraZeneca, General Electric, Ipsen, MacDougall Biomedical Communications, McCall &amp; Almy, Mintz Levin, Ropes &amp; Gray, and Vertex. STAT is the exclusive media partner of the Forum.About the World Medical Innovation ForumThe World Medical Innovation Forum is a global gathering of senior corporate, investor, and academic leaders. It was established to respond to the intensifying transformation of health care and its impact on innovation. The Forum is rooted in the belief that no matter the magnitude of</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="page" title="Page 3">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>that change, the center of health care needs to be a shared, fundamental commitment to collaborative innovation – industry and academia working together and its ability to improve patient lives.</p>
<p>For more information or to register, please go to www.worldmedicalinnovation.org.</p>
<p>About Partners HealthCare</p>
<p>Partners HealthCare is an integrated health system founded by Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Massachusetts General Hospital. In addition to its two academic medical centers, the Partners system includes community and specialty hospitals, a managed care organization, community health centers, a physician network, home health and long-term care services, and other health-related entities. Partners HealthCare is one of the nation’s leading biomedical research organizations and a principal teaching affiliate of Harvard Medical School. Partners HealthCare is a non-profit organization.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/global-impact-cancer-breakthroughs-featured-2016-world-medical-innovation-forum/">Global Impact of Cancer Breakthroughs to Be Featured at 2016 World Medical Innovation Forum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Partners Event Gathers International Cancer Leaders</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/partners-event-gathers-international-cancer-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 19:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=2153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON&#8211;(BUSINESS WIRE)&#8211;Partners HealthCare today announced the second annual World Medical Innovation Forum™, which will bring together more than 1,100 international cancer technology decision-makers from industry, investment, clinical and research communities, April 25-27, 2016 in Boston. Forum keynoters include the CEOs of Novartis, BMS, Amgen and Abbvie who will join more than 100 total speakers &#8212; <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/partners-event-gathers-international-cancer-leaders/">Partners Event Gathers International Cancer Leaders</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON&#8211;(<a href="http://www.businesswire.com/" rel="nofollow">BUSINESS WIRE</a>)&#8211;Partners HealthCare today announced the second annual <a href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fworldmedicalinnovation.org%2F&amp;esheet=51290750&amp;newsitemid=20160302005224&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=World+Medical+Innovation+Forum%E2%84%A2&amp;index=1&amp;md5=fc6287f453d6169ef1f5183a9fa6210f" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">World Medical Innovation Forum<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>, which will bring together more than 1,100 international cancer technology decision-makers from industry, investment, clinical and research communities, April 25-27, 2016 in Boston.</p>
<p>Forum keynoters include the CEOs of Novartis, BMS, Amgen and Abbvie who will join more than 100 total speakers &#8212; all experts in new cancer technology from industry, the investment community and Harvard Medical School. World Forum attendees include senior executives, investors, entrepreneurs, clinicians and scientists. The focus of the Forum is new cancer technologies and the cooperative innovation among industry, academia, government and philanthropy required to make them happen.</p>
<div class="bw-release-story">
<p>“Cancer is a major cause of death worldwide. Developing new means of treating and diagnosing cancer requires an active collaboration between clinicians, scientists, companies and investors to identify and address patient needs,” said Daniel Haber, M.D., Ph.D., Professor of Medicine at Harvard Medical School and Director of the Cancer Center at Massachusetts General Hospital. “The outcomes of this cooperation will ultimately affect the lives of patients worldwide.”</p>
<p>Over the three days, the 2016 Forum will highlight emerging cancer innovations in immunotherapy, epigenetics, early diagnosis, combination therapies, as well as curative drugs, cancer markets, the role of patients in innovation, cancer as a chronic disease and investment strategies.</p>
<p>The Forum is co-chaired by Daniel Haber, M.D., Ph.D., and Monica Bertagnolli, M.D., Chief of the Division of Surgical Oncology at Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Professor of Surgery at Harvard Medical School. Academic speakers include Harvard Medical School-appointed clinicians and investigators from Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Massachusetts General Hospital and the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute.</p>
<p>“The recent advances in the targeted treatment of cancer are extremely exciting and have set the stage for us to understand cancer biology as never before,” said Monica Bertagnolli, M.D. “While the progress in treating patients has been encouraging, cancer is a large and diverse group of diseases and it is continually evolving, making the need for innovation constant if we are to achieve our goals of prevention and cure. Pushing boundaries back requires collaboration across sectors.”</p>
<p>A highlight of the Forum is a showcase of the most promising cancer technology innovations from around the world &#8212; the 12 technologies with the potential to revolutionize cancer treatment and patient care over the next decade. The final selections, called “The Disruptive Dozen,” will be announced on the last day of the Forum. Another highlight will be rapid fire presentations by emerging cancer research stars. The “First Look: Next Wave of Cancer Breakthroughs” session will kick off the Forum at 8AM Monday April 25.</p>
<p>The World Medical Innovation Forum is organized by Partners HealthCare Innovation, a division of Partners HealthCare dedicated to advancing the commercial application of the unique capabilities of Partners’ academic medical centers. “The breadth of the topics that will be covered and the commitment to interdisciplinary engagement from international leaders across academia, finance, industry and public policy makes the Forum an unrivaled, must-attend event,” said Chris Coburn, Partners Vice President for Innovation and conference organizer.</p>
<p>Sponsors of the Forum include Novartis, Bristol-Meyers Squibb, Takeda, Amgen, Astellas, General Electric, Ipsen, AstraZeneca, MacDougall Biomedical Communications, Ropes and Gray, Mintz Levin, McCall and Almy, and Vertex.</p>
<p><b>About the World Medical Innovation Forum</b><br />
The World Medical Innovation Forum is a global gathering of senior corporate, investor and academic leaders. It was established to respond to the intensifying transformation of health care and its impact on innovation. The Forum is rooted in the belief that no matter the magnitude of that change, the center of health care needs to be a shared, fundamental commitment to collaborative innovation – industry and academia working together and its ability to improve patient lives.</p>
<p>For more information or to register, please go to <a href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.worldmedicalinnovation.org&amp;esheet=51290750&amp;newsitemid=20160302005224&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=www.worldmedicalinnovation.org&amp;index=2&amp;md5=00364c8be6ad9045955125211cccc4a1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.worldmedicalinnovation.org</a>.</p>
<p><b>About Partners HealthCare</b><br />
Partners HealthCare is an integrated health system founded by Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Massachusetts General Hospital. In addition to its two academic medical centers, the Partners system includes community and specialty hospitals, a managed care organization, community health centers, a physician network, home health and long-term care services, and other health-related entities. Partners HealthCare is one of the nation’s leading biomedical research organizations and a principal teaching affiliate of Harvard Medical School. Partners HealthCare is a non-profit organization.</p>
</div>
<div class="bw-release-contact">
<h2>Contacts</h2>
<p>Partners HealthCare<br />
<b>Partners Contact:</b><br />
Rich Copp, 617-278-1031<br />
<a href="mailto:rcopp@partners.org" target="_blank">rcopp@partners.org</a><br />
or<br />
<b>Media Contact:</b><br />
Kari Watson, 781-235-3060<br />
<a href="mailto:WMIF@macbiocom.com" target="_blank">WMIF@macbiocom.com</a></p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/partners-event-gathers-international-cancer-leaders/">Partners Event Gathers International Cancer Leaders</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can We Truly &#8220;Cure&#8221; Cancer?</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/can-we-truly-cure-cancer-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meaghan Doherty]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 20:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=1919</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Monica Bertagnolli, WMIF co-chair, chief of the Division of Surgical Oncology at Brigham and Women’s Hospital and chair of the Alliance for Clinical Trials in Oncology, a nationwide effort to test new therapies, speaks on Barack Obama&#8217;s aspirational plan in his final State of the Union to “cure cancer.” &#160; &#160;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/can-we-truly-cure-cancer-2/">Can We Truly &#8220;Cure&#8221; Cancer?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Monica Bertagnolli, WMIF co-chair, chief of the Division of Surgical Oncology at Brigham and Women’s Hospital and chair of the Alliance for Clinical Trials in Oncology, a nationwide effort to test new therapies, speaks on Barack Obama&#8217;s aspirational plan in his final State of the Union to “cure cancer.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/can-we-truly-cure-cancer-2/">Can We Truly &#8220;Cure&#8221; Cancer?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1919</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dr. Charles Czeisler Talks NASA &#038; Sleep Science</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/dr-charles-czeisler-talks-nasa-sleep-science/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meaghan Doherty]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 16:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://medforum16.wpengine.com/?p=1451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON &#8212; Dr. Charles Czeisler, MD, PhD, is up to some incredible things. He and his colleagues at Brigham and Women’s Hospital recently received NASA’s Johnson Space Center Director’s Innovation Award in Houston for their work on light systems, which will help astronauts adjust their Circadian clocks. He’s also presenting at this year’s Partners HealthCare <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/dr-charles-czeisler-talks-nasa-sleep-science/">Dr. Charles Czeisler Talks NASA &#038; Sleep Science</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON &#8212; Dr. Charles Czeisler, MD, PhD, is up to some incredible things. He and his colleagues at Brigham and Women’s Hospital recently received NASA’s Johnson Space Center Director’s Innovation Award in Houston for their work on light systems, which will help astronauts adjust their Circadian clocks. He’s also presenting at this year’s <a href="https://medtechboston.medstro.com/events/world-medical-innovation-forum-neurosciences/" target="_blank">Partners HealthCare World Medical Innovation Forum</a>, on April 27 – 29, 2015.<br />
<script src="https://apis.google.com/_/scs/apps-static/_/js/k=oz.gapi.en.NWMUTAs0kOE.O/m=auth/exm=plusone/rt=j/sv=1/d=1/ed=1/am=IQ/rs=AGLTcCPxj8CQhcqlMkFMk_msXSwX7g5HPA/t=zcms/cb=gapi.loaded_1" async=""></script></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/dr-charles-czeisler-talks-nasa-sleep-science/">Dr. Charles Czeisler Talks NASA &#038; Sleep Science</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Howard Weiner: A Doctor on a Mission to Cure MS</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/howard-weiner-a-doctor-on-a-mission-to-cure-ms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meaghan Doherty]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 16:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOSTON]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://medforum16.wpengine.com/?p=1450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON &#8212; It was during his early days as a doctor that Howard Weiner, MD, director and co-founder of the Partners Multiple Sclerosis Center at Brigham &#38; Women’s Hospital, treated a young father who had recently experienced a very bad multiple sclerosis (MS) attack. Weiner immediately identified with his patient: he was about the same age, <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/howard-weiner-a-doctor-on-a-mission-to-cure-ms/">Howard Weiner: A Doctor on a Mission to Cure MS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON &#8212; It was during his early days as a doctor that Howard Weiner, MD, director and co-founder of the <a href="http://www.partnersmscenter.org/" target="_blank">Partners Multiple Sclerosis Center</a> at <a href="http://www.brighamandwomens.org/" target="_blank">Brigham &amp; Women’s Hospital</a>, treated a young father who had recently experienced a very bad multiple sclerosis (MS) attack. Weiner immediately identified with his patient: he was about the same age, and he also had two boys. It hit him on an emotional level that there was no cure for MS.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/howard-weiner-a-doctor-on-a-mission-to-cure-ms/">Howard Weiner: A Doctor on a Mission to Cure MS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1450</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Forum Will Draw Executives</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/world-forum-will-draw-executives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 16:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=1360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sylvia Mathews Burwell, the US secretary of Health and Human Services, has a big job. Right now, for example, that involves being named in a lawsuit over the future of health care reform before the US Supreme Court. But Burwell can escape the anti-Obamacare vibes for a bit on her upcoming visit to health reform-friendly <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/world-forum-will-draw-executives/">World Forum Will Draw Executives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b class="b">Sylvia Mathews Burwell</b>, the <b class="b">US secretary of Health and Human Services</b>, has a big job.<br />
<script src="http://dnn506yrbagrg.cloudfront.net/pages/scripts/0014/1023.js?396328" async="true" type="text/javascript"></script></p>
<div id="contain">
<article class="article">
<div class="article-body">
<div class="article-text">
<p>Right now, for example, that involves being named in a lawsuit over the future of health care reform before the US Supreme Court.</p>
<p>But Burwell can escape the anti-Obamacare vibes for a bit on her upcoming visit to health reform-friendly Massachusetts.</p>
<p>She is among an elite group of health and science leaders who will speak next month at the <b class="b">W</b><b class="b">orld Medical Innovation Forum</b>, a new event sponsored by <b class="b">Partners HealthCare.</b></p>
<p>Partners, the system that includes<b class="b"> Massachusetts General</b> and <b class="b">Brigham and Women’s</b> hospitals, developed a program featuring a list of headliners who are at the forefront of research and innovation. The list of speakers includes high-profile local chief executives: <b class="b">Jeffrey Leiden</b> of Boston’s <b class="b">Vertex Pharmaceuticals</b>, <b class="b">Michael Mahoney</b> of Marlborough-based <b class="b">Boston Scientific</b>,<b class="b"> Deborah Dunsire</b> of Watertown-based <b class="b">Forum Pharmaceuticals</b>, and from Cambridge, <b class="b">David Meeker</b> of <b class="b">Genzyme,</b> and <b class="b">George Scangos</b> of <b class="b">Biogen Idec.</b></p>
<p>Also on the schedule is <b class="b">Ann Romney</b>, who is the wife of the former Massachusetts governor and presidential candidate, and an ambassador for multiple sclerosis patients.</p>
<p>Brigham last year named its <b class="b">Center for Neurologic Diseases</b> for Romney, who was diagnosed with MS in 1998.</p>
<p>The innovation forum, slated for April 27 to 29 at the <b class="b">Westin Copley Place</b> hotel, will be centered on neuroscience.</p>
<p>Of course, being sponsored by the state’s biggest health system, the event will include plenty of speakers with Partners on their name tags.</p>
</div>
</div>
</article>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/world-forum-will-draw-executives/">World Forum Will Draw Executives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1360</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Partners HealthCare Announces Keynote Speakers for the 2015 World Medical Innovation Forum</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/partners-healthcare-announces-keynote-speakers-for-the-2015-world-medical-innovation-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WMIF Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 22:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=1269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON &#8212; Partners HealthCare today announced the keynote speakers, including several of the health industry’s most well-known and respected chief executives, for the first annual World Medical Innovation Forum™, which will bring together more than 1,000 international decision-makers from the life sciences, health care, academic and investment communities on April 27-29, 2015, in Boston to <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/partners-healthcare-announces-keynote-speakers-for-the-2015-world-medical-innovation-forum/">Partners HealthCare Announces Keynote Speakers for the 2015 World Medical Innovation Forum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BOSTON &#8212; Partners HealthCare today announced the keynote speakers, including several of the health industry’s most well-known and respected chief executives, for the first annual <a class="icon " href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fworldmedicalinnovation.org%2F&amp;esheet=51045489&amp;newsitemid=20150224005677&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=World+Medical+Innovation+Forum%E2%84%A2&amp;index=1&amp;md5=5ed5aa5afbb320e497f0d7326b5c6c1c" target="_new">World Medical Innovation Forum<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>, which will bring together more than 1,000 international decision-makers from the life sciences, health care, academic and investment communities on April 27-29, 2015, in Boston to discuss the most compelling advances in neuroscience technology, care and research.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/partners-healthcare-announces-keynote-speakers-for-the-2015-world-medical-innovation-forum/">Partners HealthCare Announces Keynote Speakers for the 2015 World Medical Innovation Forum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1269</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ann Romney campaigning hard for medical research</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/ann-romney-campaigning-hard-for-medical-research/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Transmit Studio]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BELMONT — Ann Romney knows a lot about political campaigns. Win or lose, there’s one thing you gain for sure: a network of people with an awful lot of money. They couldn’t put her husband, Mitt, in the White House, but she’s now hoping everyone will get behind her to launch the Ann Romney Center <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/ann-romney-campaigning-hard-for-medical-research/">Ann Romney campaigning hard for medical research</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BELMONT — Ann Romney knows a lot about political campaigns. Win or lose, there’s one thing you gain for sure: a network of people with an awful lot of money.</p>
<p>They couldn’t put her husband, Mitt, in the White House, but she’s now hoping everyone will get behind her to launch the <a class="a" href="http://www.bwhannromneycenter.org/">Ann Romney Center for Neurologic Diseases</a> at Brigham and Women’s Hospital. Her goal is to create a new model for research and funding, setting out to raise $50 million over the next year to help find treatments and cures for five conditions: multiple sclerosis, Alzheimer’s, Lou Gehrig’s (ALS), Parkinson’s, and brain tumors.</p>
<p>The Romneys are seeding the center with what Ann calls a “substantial gift.” And I trust that it is big. Before Mitt’s two failed presidential bids and before he served as our governor, he made a fortune as founder of Bain Capital, the Boston buyout firm.</p>
<p>This is hardly a vanity project for Mrs. Romney. She has lived for 16 years with MS, a chronic disease of the immune system in which nerves deteriorate, causing symptoms as severe as paralysis. Her doctor, Howard Weiner, is at the Brigham and the idea for a new center came two years ago following a routine visit. Romney’s MS, initially treated with steroids, has been in remission for more than a decade and is now managed by a healthy diet and exercise.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/ann-romney-campaigning-hard-for-medical-research/">Ann Romney campaigning hard for medical research</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">665</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breakthrough Replicates Human Brain Cells for Use in Alzheimer’s Research</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/breakthrough-replicates-human-brain-cells-for-use-in-alzheimers-research/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Transmit Studio]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldmedicalinnovation.org/?p=667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For the first time, and to the astonishment of many of their colleagues, researchers created what they call Alzheimer’s in a Dish — a petri dish with human brain cells that develop the telltale structures of Alzheimer’s disease. In doing so, they resolved a longstanding problem of how to study Alzheimer’s and search for drugs <span class="continue-link">...</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/breakthrough-replicates-human-brain-cells-for-use-in-alzheimers-research/">Breakthrough Replicates Human Brain Cells for Use in Alzheimer’s Research</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="story-continues-1" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="435" data-total-count="435">For the first time, and to the astonishment of many of their colleagues, researchers created what they call <a class="meta-classifier" title="In-depth reference and news articles about Alzheimer's Disease." href="http://health.nytimes.com/health/guides/disease/alzheimers-disease/overview.html?inline=nyt-classifier">Alzheimer’s</a> in a Dish — a petri dish with human brain cells that develop the telltale structures of Alzheimer’s disease. In doing so, they resolved a longstanding problem of how to study Alzheimer’s and search for drugs to treat it; the best they had until now were mice that developed an imperfect form of the disease.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="479" data-total-count="914">The key to their success, said the lead researcher, Rudolph E. Tanzi of <a title="More articles about Massachusetts General Hospital" href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/organizations/m/massachusetts_general_hospital/index.html?inline=nyt-org">Massachusetts General Hospital</a> in Boston, was a suggestion by his colleague Doo Yeon Kim to grow human brain cells in a gel, where they formed networks as in an actual brain. They gave the neurons genes for Alzheimer’s disease. Within weeks they saw the hard Brillo-like clumps known as plaques and then the twisted spaghetti-like coils known as tangles — the defining features of Alzheimer’s disease.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/breakthrough-replicates-human-brain-cells-for-use-in-alzheimers-research/">Breakthrough Replicates Human Brain Cells for Use in Alzheimer’s Research</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/partners-wmif-2016/">World Medical Innovation Forum</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">667</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
